hello everyone uh I'm s I'm very glad to
get the invite to uh present this
multimod agent area uh I saw you already
uh listened the similar the exact same
area multi model agent last week uh
hopefully I I I would bring something
new in this direction so first I want to
show this uh plot uh to everyone so how
you can see how crazy it is right uh in
the past four uh five years uh almost
all the benchmarks get
saturated and now we have the last one
which is the
this uh the one proposed this year human
last exam seems like when we solve this
one they solve
HR uh I'm not sure whether we can solve
it uh this year but I and I believe we
have a better much better result for
this data set this benchmarks by end of
this
year okay since we have so much so
powerful Frontier Foundation
models then what we should do on those
models how we could leverage them to
make our world make aity better I think
the answer is Agent We Believe the
multimodal AI agent is the next
generation of
applications why it's
because we want agent not just reading
text we want the agent can hear can see
can speak can feel even and we want
agents that to process a task like
human that because most of the task like
when we they
when we do in computer they involves
multiple apps
interfaces so power with those the new
Advanced the the language model or the
large Foundation model which is uh
Vision language action
models it could make the the digital
interactions more accessible more
automated and increase the humans
production it so okay so what the status
of the multi agent how far it is
actually it's not far
away we already see uh a lot of the
multimodal agents be used in the real
world
or or some of them is using real world I
say some of them in the in the still in
the research like for example the coding
agent I think some of you maybe lot of
you are using the the coding assistant
or agent products like the curso rep
plate or D you know daily work or or
research and those those agents is not
only that can accept the the code text
they also can let you to upload the
images and they could to generate the
code or fix your back through the image
us web agents the web agents is is also
a multi model agent that the agent could
help you not help you could automate
some control in your browser or apps
same as the mobile agents and the even
physical agent super amazing right so
this is uh a robot called helex from
figure AI if not just show the the you
interact with a single robot even you
could let robot and robot collaborate
together through the power for the this
Foundation models so all those agents
some of them in production some of is
studing research some of is a d
stage and I believe we are going to have
more and more this type of Applied use
cases of M model
agents so the question
is how are we going to develop them and
what the import what the challenging for
developing those multimodel agents and
what is the important component what we
should focus on so this is today's
agenda I will talk about the multimodal
agents from this three areas first is
environment Benchmark we need a a
Interactive envirment
we need the this development can be more
configurable expandable not just static
benchmarks for mul mod
agent we need a
data how we get data to CH our multi
model
agent the third one
is what the model we should build on we
interact with computers every
day I use that to perform a lot of
different tasks including like a well
web browsing uh editing some personal
videos uh manag our files doing some
analyze or doing coding to to implement
some soft
softwares and the for those
tasks um they are not just the we it's
not just for those task it's not just in
interact with a single app it is
workflow that will involve multiple
applications
through gu or
C and with multi multimodel
agents it could it have a big potential
that can help us
to revolutionize this interaction
between us and this computer
environment the agents can follow our
high level natural language
instruction and to automatically to do
those interactions
for example in this image in this in
this slide there's a task
called update the bookkeeping sheet with
my recent transactions over the past few
days in the provided folder it is a very
boring
task for this type of task I think
everyone would like to have a a agent to
help them process those talk if
there is one however to build L agents
you you need how can you trust L agents
we need to have a
benchmark So currently there is a major
challenge in developing those multimodel
agents that uh we don't have a
benchmark that is depends on the real
interactive
environment that that this this
environment can cover the more diverse
and the complex the real world the
computer
use uh the scenarios and also can
support the different operating system
interfaces
apps so with this type of
Benchmark after the agent pass that
Benchmark we can TR we can trust uh this
agent for our daily use
So currently uh we they have some they
already have some good benchmarks but
they are not have this properties I just
mentioned like the manal web the manal
web is a real good Benchmark they
include a lot of good the kind of the
real testing however for each the the
test in the mental web it it it has only
single
demonstrations without the executable
enironment so the funtion from the M web
is uh for each task there is only single
solution which is not true
100% And with that Benchmark it would uh
wrong to to make a longly long make some
would paralyze some alternative to
correct solution the web arena is
another good Benchmark it is an
executable
development however it simplified the
observations and actions space that it
only cover very limit the task and
applications or domains like it only
cover the web navigations on a few uh
website domain in domains so in last one
is
restrict the the testing you the the use
cases for the
agents um and also it cannot use to
evaluate the some open open man tasks uh
in a complex real world
scenarios um that maybe it require some
task
require uh the navigating between
multiple different applications and
interfaces in the open domain to address
this gap between uh the development uh
the the real the type real world use
case and the mod development the the
development model
development uh the simulation
environment so we introduce the OS
word um this is the first the scalable
and the the real computer environment
for uh development and the benchmarking
of multi multi model
agents um why it is I we say is is a
real computer environment it's and and
and it could be used for the both
development and the benchmarking of the
multimodel agents as because the O word
first this development allows the the
free from the law free from the keyboard
mouse control of the the real Computer
Applications and it's not the the fix
the the the evaluation set you could to
config your
tasks uh and execute those
tasks through this in uh and through
this interactive way so this one then
you can use the O Earth word to evaluate
is some open-ended computer
tasks and with the arit applications so
it's not
fix uh maybe you can do ranging from
different use case like a software
development use case or image editing
use case the O word can serve
as a unified real world uh real computer
developments
that allows the use users so in way they
can allow users to define the agent
task Define new agent
task without to
build this
new uh domain specific simulation
environment so it's at an environment
the Earth world is more
flexible and look and the give the users
more
control uh for
the the development design for their for
their for the scenarios they care so
let's see how we going to use the OS
word to create the different
task the first for each task you have a
natural language task instruction for
for the task so you see here uh you have
a a task you want to uh create this
uh uh testing
environment updating this one is I just
mentioned this task updating is uh book
sheet and with this
instruction in the earthw they provide
uh the initial State setup for this
instruction so the setup is uh it's a f
you just need to create this
file in in this file they include
multiple components
the right part is you need to config uh
the initial
tasks uh like this Excel files uh means
the
tasks and also you need to uh add what
is your post
processing um and the uh those
configurations and also where can you
can to retrieve the files and the
information yeah yellow part and the
last one is how you going to
evaluate uh after you uh finish the task
in the enironment after you config the
your initial State the
setup uh the Earth words the will
initialize the comp this computer T this
this development with a virtual machine
and in the virion machine uh they will
initialize so the initialization will
will start wrong in this ver machine and
you get the initial States of uh of the
test
development that's very
convenient so for example
uh at this moment um you could use this
virtual machine to restore the task uh
again and again just to reuse this
virtual
machine
uh and because of we use this verion
machine so it's it's a safe isolated
environment you don't need to worry
about um
some some some damage in irreversible
the damages uh when testing so when the
task uh enironment gets set
up the then you can start to have to run
your agent to interact with this
enironment for example you can use tp4
way to create agent and interact with
this
environment or you can use any other
open source model to build the
agent the agent will
receive uh or observe uh different
information that can be provided by the
environment
first of course is the user query the
natural langage instruction from
user and also uh it can to receive the
observations from the development such
as the
screenshot uh look accessibility
tree uh and some customized the streams
maybe the terminal
output so in so here is a example like
the left side is a it's called a set of
mask which is a screenshot plus some uh
plus the the the the information you
expect from accessibility tree that you
can uh add those the label like uh in
the uh in the image so it make uh the
they can provide more information of
just
screenshot and also the left right side
is is the Dom tree um is is
accessibility but for for website do
tree so after you the agent receive
those observations of course it's not
say like every agent need all
observations it depends your agent you
if use you are Vision based agent maybe
only use the uh screenshot or so if is a
tax based agent maybe you only use
accessibility tree it depends on what
agent uh you you're going to build for
to interact with your environment
so after you receive those observations
the agent will uh to it depends how you
create agent but agent finally will
generate some ex executable actions like
you click some position or you will Jack
some some content Jack some box and
Etc at uh Manu that's so manipulate the
keyboard and and mouse uh
and the then each of those actions uh
will be uh present represented using it
Cod streen and to generated by agent and
then the development uh the simulator
will execute uh those the C streams uh
in the watching machine and you will get
then you will get the new observations
now uh the O word that we are using the
the Pi Auto gui3 uh to uh control mouse
and keyboard uh this is where we used
the library so between the so this is
this interaction Loop will will continue
based on U the your instruction uh here
will repeat multiple steps until uh it
terminated maybe it's down or fail or
it it's reach the the max number of STS
use that uh in our experiment we that is
the 15 and the
50 so after you so now you you can you
can you can from you set up the task
until you then you run your task and
then after task you stop uh you get a
results then you will do evaluation on
your task in this devel in OS word in OS
word is is different from from other
benchmarks we implement this uh
execution based uh the the the reward
function
um so when uh when the when when when
the final step reach the goal of course
they'll get a positive reward uh or even
if partially achieved we get a th some
some number between zero one if not if
totally failed it will get zero
to get this reward we are not just use
uh uh the single the the evaluation
magic um to so here is to evaluate this
successful execution of uh those
task
um we we thinking there is no single way
to
evaluate the the successful or fail
uh for the task so we make this
evaluation more
open what is open so open means that you
can
construct the evaluation script by
yourself in
development because some some task you
need to retrieval some task you need to
match to to evaluate your
task so we we use this example wise the
evaluation
to design the evaluation matri for tasks
so not just the fixed one so it's a open
one that you can base on different task
to to design your different
matrics so that you can uh uh uh
facilitate the the diversity of the
task uh and and could make a the
evaluation more reliable especially for
the for this complex real world
open-ended tasks so we create this a
powerful OS World
development uh so that the people can
use this evelopment to benchmarking
their multimodel
agents but besides we build this
development of course we also build uh a
benchmark uh on top of os word
uh here we introduce the
369 uh real world computer tasks uh that
uh uh
involve uh widely used the the web or
desktop apps uh like
the uh like uh it's office OS and da use
workflow and the
professionals all of them each task is
uh is is we we did a lot of ret search
on in the internet so all them is based
on the real world the computer use cases
The
Experience um and then we ask the the
people who had the Cs background to uh
interact with the the the initial stated
the initialized development in word
um um and the and the and and interact
with the elment and the record those uh
the
trajectories uh and also handcrafted the
lots of the execution execution uh
evaluation script the evaluation scripts
execution based evaluation evaluation
scripts to verify the task completion so
in the left side you can see the
distribution of the different tasks so
total they have
369 and uh 100 is a it's a workflow task
which is multi app mean this task need
to jump jump between jump across
different apps multiple apps and they
have the 268 which is roughly 70% is a
single app and in those uh those uh
tasks some of them uh which is roughly
20% is through uh the the other data set
like lab Arena
uh and there's a special here is we also
add the 30 task which is invisible
because uh you need to also know U you
also know agent should also know how to
say no to to the
user so we think adding the invisible uh
task is important to make it more
comprehensive for all the you for the
finar
testing and we also have a small number
of 43 uh task for Windows not just
ons and as I said because we we thinking
this example based the evaluation script
I mean uh it's it's very important for
the the real world evaluation on
multimodel agents uh we construct the
134 evaluation script on
369 example the samples so you can see
the ratio is very big so here is some
some examples samples uh we samples from
our uh
300 uh the the the F of the in our
benchmark so you can see uh the C very
diverse the the apps and uh cause
different the the user intent but we
compared the our Benchmark with the
current existing popular benchmarks uh
from the those
different perspective such as uh whether
it provides the controllable
executable environment or whether it's
easy to scale to the new
environment or it can support the multi
model or whether it could be do the
class app task class app tasks or it
could while it could uh start Task from
intermediate the in state and so on so
we can see our a benchmark is to uh have
more
powerful more I mean the C different the
the
scenarios request as
a as a as a benchmark for the multimodal
agents and the in right side we also did
some analysis how complicated the task
uh in the OS World Benchmark we come we
did some comp comparison with the web
Arena so the green sorry the the the the
blue is vabina and the yellow is O word
uh
the uh the medium completion time for
Vina is roughly uh 30 40 seconds and for
the in O world the median completion
time is
roughly 100 100 maybe 110
seconds um and they also have a some
uh significant the number of EX maybe
need even more even even need 900
seconds or even more means that the
complexity of this Benchmark is also
higher than the existing benchmarks we
after we create a benchmark we test The
Benchmark uh with uh the state of art
the LM or VM uh from the open source and
also cross Source the
uh the foundation models like uh uh gbt
4 gni cloud and
Etc and the left side is the the plumps
we use we designed the four different
testing the
settings uh through through based on
different
observation uh the they are the one is
only half accessibility which could be
the the L can uh directly to run it and
second one is a only screenshot which is
pure vision and third one is a
screenshot plus
accessibility and the fourth one is set
of
marks we did some on
the uh some some simplification on
accessibility tree because usually
accessibility is very long uh and
include a lot of the Redundant
information
so we did some simplification to reduce
them uh to to to sh the length of the
this text representation so this is the
the results the the the numbers we
get uh let's do
some some analysis on this
table so first let's see the at the
bottom of this table is a human
performance
uh roughly 70 to 75 percent percent
percent success
rate and if you go to see the the
performance of uh those
the the step art open source and the
frontier close Source model is still far
behind uh far from the the real human
performance on those uh daily use task
it's not like a super hard task it's a
daily use
tasks and second uh uh you you see like
a from different the uh you the
scenarios Human Performance is kind of
stable it's it's plus
minus 3 to
5% but for the uh those Frontier models
the uh large Foundation models the per
performance Chang
dramatically and even the model from
same company like you see the for
example
uh in the in this okay in the set of
Mark the gbd4 and gbt
40 is the performance Gap is huge right
it's it's 10 10% Gap even the
performance since the performance only
just 20% have 10% Gap and of course so
this is table is result is uh we get
last year and this year they have new
models from local uh from the uh from
from those uh vendors uh the open a and
the TR uh they have some bigger pment on
there but the still it's far away from
the uh from the human performance we see
we did some analysis on what
factors uh influence this the
performance the first we did some
analysis on the screenshot resolution so
we
found
um so first we we so one point so in the
in the in the y axis is a successful
rate and x-axis is a down sampling rate
so we so we because of VM uh is most of
VM is still TR very small resolu not
very small but it's comparing with now
we have better resolution but usually
the we I'm not at the full resolution is
CH on some a smaller one so we do some
down sampling on the uh on the
resolution and then we we calculate then
then we R evaluation in uh uh GPT 4
screenshot as you improve the screenshot
it get a better
performance but in so it's I think the
trend still is improved but still this
is noise here but is still improve but
not as much as not as clear as the
screenshot I think it's because so
include also include some the uh they
have some extra information it gets from
the accessibility tree based on so they
have some t
information inside so it decrease the
impact of the resolution and then we
also doing some analysis on the uh how
much the uh the the historic historic
context will uh influence the final
performance
so we did this uh we we choose different
number of the the the the L the
lens uh we
found in the
gb4 is improved as you add more and more
the the historical uh the information
the
steps but in a in a screenshot one it's
doesn't it even make it it's even
worse we think it's mainly it's because
uh the S so have like I said it include
those the information from the text
representation
accessibility uh and our is perform is
the current Foundation model is perform
better on the Tex rather than the the
pure original image so I think so we
think that is the reason uh getting
better and better with more and more
context but for the screenshot it
getting getting worse I think is still
is because how the the Cent the the
foundation model uh is not be well ched
for the computer use is scenarios so uh
it means uh we need to it's still have a
a gap like the the the open source a
community or the close Source companies
need to improve uh those uh the vision
capabilities in the foundation model if
we want to get a better multimodel agent
for computer use and in the right side
it's it's a it's a length distribution
of the accessibility tree so although
you can add the more and more low stex
representation uh in the multimodel
agent and they can get better
performance but they have the issue
there it's uh accept acceptability tree
is super long um so roughly is at 90% %
percentile is
6k so if we want to add more uh the his
the hisory the the context then we need
to find a way to get a uh more uh more
simplify OB to C more concise
flexibility CH so maybe they have some
work how to select the relevant
information in the cability tree before
you fit into the system but when you do
this step Maybe maybe you your system
will be slow because you need do this
information to do maybe you need to tr
another big model to do this information
processing uh on on you know that add
the actual latency
there and we also analyze the model
performance on the upang to and windows
we found that their correlation is
pretty high it's s
and so which means like uh we could use
the OS word framework it will be
effective uh you could to uh get uh if
you can Ty the model in good in one in
one scenario should be uh you it should
be effectively transferred to another
environment
uh and we also did uh uh some operation
like if when we uh change the position
side uh of the windows in the the
different app windows in the in the
screen uh the the results also show very
different so which means uh uh uh it
still means like the model is not the
the found those Foundation model is not
very robust to the for the for this type
of the disturb disturbance so so through
this we can find have still is they have
a lot of work we should we need to
improve right
um and uh good news is uh recently they
have a lot of the new progress in this
areas uh and Tropic uh they have this
new Cloud 3.5 and also the 3.7 and we
can see the the very significant
Improvement uh from here 14
15% to
22% but still far away from Human
72% of course if you increase the number
of steps from 15 to 50 uh it's getting
better but still still have a big G and
open AI also have this new model called
operator the cud
um and in our recent performance or CA
sorry in the recent performance uh we
can see uh open ey is significantly
better than um the C
3.5
uh and the at the 200 St they can get
even
38% of comparing R like maybe only have
% uh four months ago so it's improved
super fast um but the this this is like
you have 200 steps but most of task in
the osw is roughly uh should be most of
it can be solved under the 15 or even 20
steps so which means uh they still have
a big Improvement they have big space to
improve the the M multimodel agent for
the for this computer use okay so uh
this is through the environment and The
Benchmark discussion you know uh we we
have we have made a big a lot of great
progress on this computer use areas for
multi model agent but still they have a
lot of uh the uh stuff we need to
improve uh they have still have a lot of
opportunities there
now after this let's go to the data part
since we still need the data to chain
our
model to for for the agent
training I think we have a bigger
challenge than we doing the LM
training
why because the agent model is not a a a
single step it's a multi step it's a
trajectory collecting a trajectory data
is super
expensive and second is it's very hard
to directly to to to get the dejected
data by CL the internet and and and
second even you say you have enough
money I can I can just to hire people to
C data but to to do those annotation to
C Theory data is very time consuming and
it limits this the
scalability not good for the scaling
law the the cost and the time consuming
of the the data collection through human
and also there's no free large scale
trajectory purpose you can call then
what we
do
okay why don't we like the model to Sy
here I want to discuss this paper called
the agent CH uh to which is uh to
synthesize the agent trajectories uh
through this guiding play way strategy
uh with Vib tutorial but what does it
mean um so first we know they have a lot
of the a large collection of the
tutorial like tutorial like text uh in
the internet right and the those text uh
they they provide the the step-by-step
guidance on how to perform different
tasks uh so we read it we we read those
tutorial to then how to interact with
different app and complete different
tasks in in our you know DUI
developments and and then those
tutorials the they cover different the
the
scenarios so we could to systematically
to filterate
uh or filtering those instruction
contents uh from
internet and of course those data is not
that clean because it's written for
human so they have a lot of noise text
uh descriptions and and of course HTML
formats
there so so we need to extract the the
valuable the knowledges uh that uh
that knowledge the steps from from the
those tutorial like
text uh and then transform those
unstructured text into uh into a
structured the the the agent
trajectories uh with the the the the
definition or high level description of
the
task uh that make it to allow the the
agent to use to to tr and mimic the
human task
completion so in the agent trick uh they
have the three stages to do
this the first stage is called the
automatic uh tutorial collection from
internet so in this that we as I just
roughly described these tracks and the
uh and the filter LS data from the
internet using a bunch of fistic the
filtering and and some class F like with
the fast text and uh then then transform
it into some
structured uh the format
uh with using
LM and step two is uh the guided replay
for those trajectory generation which is
using uh vrm Vision language model agent
to execute those tutorials based on the
structure tutorial the structure steps
and one is step by step and through that
we will to collect the the high level
trajectories including the the high
level description of the task uh the
observation of each step and the and the
re reason reasoning of each step and the
final
actions and then given those
data uh we will we will run a evalue run
a separate evaluator to evaluate look to
assess the quality of the
trajectory uh to ensure the to fil out
some bad trajectories or low quality
ones uh to maintain to make sure it's to
to ensure this the the effectiveness of
this data for the
chy and the step three is we need
verified those agent by training a model
and F the for the agent models to
demonstrate uh the improvements and uh
the significance of performance
Improvement across different benchmarks
so that is roughly a step for three
stages for agent check
so like I described is three step let's
go a little bit deeper about each step
the first step is like is this a
tutorial collection from internet so we
start from some uh the big uh large
Corpus like a r pajama
dclm uh then
we did the the using the some
filtering uh with based on keyword words
or some structure
features uh and we did after this step
we filter maybe uh
99% of
data uh and then for the remaining data
we extract the sub subsets a subset of
the the remaining data the pre pre the
filter data and use the LM to uh did
some
ation it is a good uh it is a good data
is a bad data for uh for for the as the
tutorial and then after this
annotation uh we TR a f Tex classile and
use that one to classify all the the
whole uh the filter
data and this up then when you get this
uh the tutorial data we run another
round of M to paraphrase those data to
follow some predefined the the the
format uh
that uh used for the the guided for guid
rep plan for the stage two so this is
the this is the data flow the the flow I
the follow step one when you to the
prefatory so you can see we uh use some
um the theistic
filters uh to do the the first step the
data filter and you can see like uh just
after this one two three the six step
you could it will filter out more than
99.9% data and uh after you get this
filter data we at we select some set we
select a small set small number of the
data
and use the the prom LM to classify is a
DUI tutorial or not this is the prompt
we
use uh after we do that we we also have
the human to do some to to sample some
of to verify if find that F1 score is
pretty high it's like eight they can get
rough 88
89% and we fund uh for some
long text long text the the the
documents U the L is performed better
than the human uh when they embat the
tutorial in the long
context which is normal uh which is is
which is not surprised uh but uh so in
this way we we watch after the LM on the
long context
classification then after we filtered
those tutorial data then we
formalize uh the the tutorial data into
a specific the structure the format that
we want to use to for for the model for
the model for the the the replay the
guided
replay um here we uh organized uh so the
left side is the prump we used go so we
want to through this prompt we want to
convert uh the
tutorial uh into this six into five five
parts first is uh the the plat the
platform and the target developments
that specify uh what is operating system
what software versions so that be used
for the initial
State uh and second one is the task
description which to provide concise
problem
statements uh which is the the the
instruction the third one is the
prerequisites which requ the
dependencies background knowledges and
third and fourth one is this step by
step the the
instructions uh which include this uh
reing guidance and a command uh syntax
and the last one is the expected outcome
which can you which is used for the
verification or success uh indicators so
after we get this after we
paraphrase the tutorial then we get this
structured tutorial and then uh we
create a where am agent uh and fit into
this step bystep tutorial and the agent
where to uh start to
run um the interactor with the the
development step by
step uh through this observation action
Loop
uh and through this uh after the whole
execution we will record it all the
observation
action um intermediate reasoning
uh the whole
trajectories and then then those will
fit into uh another VM evaluator to
assess the quality or correctness of the
trajectory and ensure uh we we got uh
high quality data so here is a example
of uh in our in our the the finalized
dat the final version of the data after
you doing all
steps
um so you could see the left side is the
observation uh sequence and right side
including the the the action the the S
each step and the the the actions the
action code for each step so comparing
the the data we collect using the agent
check with uh the PRI works the pr the
other the uh data set people use to CH
model
first our data could be through agent
you can collect much more
data here we show this 10K 10K is not
the maximum we just do some of them it
could be much
bigger and the second the complexity of
uh the data is not not not low actually
it's pretty good they the every step is
T
steps and you also will have a lot of
the the
information you will you will have HTML
you will have have accessibility you
also will have reasoning you support you
could get videos you can get a
screenshots and you can cover different
websites so the agent trick it maintains
the diversity and the realism because
it's from Real World and it's also
addressing the scalability
issues uh that the human anot data may
have uh given the the The Bu so here is
the the distribution of the the the
trajectories from the the so this is
distrib the left side is the the
distributions the the data we uh the
different number of trajectory from
different the
websites uh on the right side it's uh
from the high level different vertical
different domains what's the the
distribution and in the
data uh so you can see the how
uh you can see how the the coverage of
the data set the the domains through in
the agent check the uh I mean say like
the data set created by the agent so we
did some the like we said we F tun the
model to check the um the performance
the to to to see the how good uh this uh
synthesiz data comparing with other
human anot human annotated data uh in
the uh the benchmarks to train the age
in the in the benchmarks so we did it on
this comparison on the web Rea data set
or
Benchmark yeah and the models trend on
agent trick data significantly out of
from um both uh I think open source and
even close Source be for all models so
which
demonstrate uh the just synthesized
trajectories also it it's also high
quality and it's also can use to CH the
uh a b model this is uh about how we do
use the agent check to to do the data
synthesis for GUI agent uh I think a
take away from this agent check work is
uh leveraging the internet Corpus is
still a important way because they have
diverse task
resources uh and second is the um um
we second is the um in the in we we the
reasoning and the
reflection uh it reason reason
reflection is very
important uh the the the factor for the
trajectory which we will talk about in
the model side
later yeah but however we still have a
issue here is because you for each uh
instruction you still only get a single
trajectory so which uh is a issue that
the uh not like you only have a single
solution for for for each inst for the
query it could be have mul instruction
so still have this issue here because
it's only it's it's it's IM it's only a
imitation learning
process but I think of we have uh the
solution for it is OS word so you can
use agent trick to uh to to create a
data for sft training and then you can
use that the high level instruction and
and run in the OS word or for the second
state the io chain and then you can
solve this exploitation
exploration process great so we we we
try to answer the question like we can
use the data synthesis to uh make the
existing real Vision language model be
performed better on the the GUI agent
tasks then then we so the second the
next I want to discuss is when you do
data
synthesis for to improve this action
capability action C capability for agent
for external task how how about it could
also help
for your
internal the task
itself like understanding we know like
the vision Lang model is ched for the
understanding and if we want to do it
can we call from web data website is the
website have this type of data I think
answer is not really
then how can we synthesize so first let
me see like why we need do it why we
want to synthesize this type of the
action data for multi model multi model
LM to for understanding understanding
should
be the the the capability of skills it
have but actually it's not
perfect what is far from perfect on the
open source model so here is the four
examples from the four
different perspective to explain why we
need the model to itself can do the
action calling to improve
understanding all those task either they
need more
frr Vision capability or they need some
reasoning capabilities or need some
external knowledge so here we introduce
a tackle uh which is through uh
synthesize this CH of s and action data
to improve the multi model understanding
capabilities through uh adding this
action calling capabilities uh skilles
in a uh in a model so this is some
examples we showed uh uh after adding
this action calling capability which is
ch through uh the the the synthetic data
we will discuss
later it can generate uh the result
thoughts and the actions and through
observations they will they will do
again until they get the results so this
is the one example like to uh we we just
show this failed in this uh lava
model and this another one is uh is
called
localization uh and the functions visual
visual functions and this is to query
the external knowledge the text
knowledge so not just the vision model
only and this mix the vision OCR and
some the the
calculate calculate uh the the
capabilities okay so let let's talk
let's go back how then how we create
this uh a synthetic pipeline
um for the for to to to syn to generate
this data for the for the
F uh CH there is a lot of details here
but don't worry let's explain the one by
one uh it's not that
complicated uh the first for this data s
pipeline they have like two part first
part is called the modelbased generation
and the bottom part is a programmatic a
programmatic
generation so in a model based
generation uh First We Take the 15 uh
image QA uh we get those image and QA
pirs at input and we pumped then pump
the the model the the frontier models I
say like you have you have this image
and the qu pair let generate the the
chum thought and action
given those the the
action all called action
LIF or uh TR of thought if uh they do
not have the uh relevant the the
relevant uh action in the
list uh other then it will generate and
after it generate uh either the CH of
thought with action or CH of thought
without action then we we will verify
the the the outcome the
output uh if it's correct then we will
pass
it uh if it's not then we will convert
this this PA as the direct answer PA so
in this way you will get the the data
not all of them have the action some of
them have action some of them only have
jump thought some of and without this
direct answer so that is
first this is part the top part and in
the bottom part we do the pro
programmatical
generation this way is we do not have
the Qs in in in this gener in this uh
programmatic generation process so we
only have the image then we use the
model whe maybe detection model depth
model OCR model uh and different models
and also could be human to label some
data some
box and we get those St annotations in
the image and we designed some manually
templates and use that to
generate the the QA
PS uh and through that we can to
synthesize what actions in a uh formula
answer to question to answer so this is
the template we use to do the
programmatic generation so uh some some
of them is about counting some of them
is about uh the two 2D special reasoning
or 3D special reasoning uh some of them
is the mixed understanding and Counting
or so if we try to um
mimic uh different the reasoning or the
the action call needed to answer
different type of the uh the the
questions and the the then here the the
bottom is the action sets which cover
like
OCR uh get object
localization death
estimation and Club regular to me to M
um no to m to me um and uh qu language
model accurate soft math equation is
pretty pretty diverse so so through this
two way we collect the data and of
course in this data we we need to we we
there have some of them is the the chain
of s action data some of them is not
then we we need to do some analysis on
the those data uh and test on the
benchmarks so first one we through our
the experiment first one we found um to
get the model get the the the multi
model Foundation models to have this
reasoning or action C capabilities you
need to use f
tuning uh in the results we found f
short or in context planing and doesn't
work and the second
is
um we found they have
comparing uh for for the tasks with this
action adding this action capabilities
it's really to improve the the
capability to uh solve uh the task it
cannot solve before to improve their
understanding capabilities which means
the the even the understanding this cap
this
capabilities it it also could be
enhanced by adding adding external tools
and make it to through this function
call or to calling to improve it which
is not suffice but the uh it's also
interesting to see this uh positive
results so it can give the give us a
different the another direction are when
how can we how could we improving uh our
models on on understanding and uh this
is the second uh observation we find the
best cot data so the the CT data uh we
we the the best one which can almost uh
to uh is is is it is test on the
different the scenarios see uh it test
on only this a okay weate blink Mass
with
mmu it is almost improve all the tasks
which means that uh this so adding this
action capability in the model in a data
set sorry act to create this CH of s
action data it can
improve and with this data TR model MTI
that model it can improve the uh the the
model understanding capability in
general not like I just improve one
model one one Ben and the third
observation from this uh uh the taco
experiments on the C the CH AC data set
we we find the quality is more important
than quantity not just ad more you will
get a better performance okay uh so this
paper is talk about how we could to uh
add in the action code capability into
the multi model language model or
Foundation model and it and first you
need to find to a model not through the
few shot and second is C data is
consistent to improve those uh the
models uh the uh through this funing um
on the this instruction this synthesiz
data and the fourth one is the quality
it's more important quity which is not
uh new but uh it's still it's some some
lessons we learned from from
here so so here is we have discussed
about the development
benchmarking uh and the data syesis I
think now uh you already have the the uh
comprehensive view holistic view about
uh about this multi agent areas uh if
you want to test the agent if you want
to generate the data and then if you
want to do the a uh in the environment
uh you already have those tools and you
can start to uh create your multi Model
A so the last one I want to spend some
time talk about the model although I'm
not saying that this the best model but
I think you can maybe you can learn from
some insight from this model I think so
right now uh every have new models uh
um so this they always have have a
better one so I hope like uh we can
discuss some different things about
model here so I want to discuss this
paper is AR with our paper which is a
unified pure Vision uh model for the GUI
agent for the G
agents we find they have a three uh the
not not problem three issues like we we
want to
solve uh first is most of gii agent is
tax based tax user tax representation
like accessibility
G uh second uh the video grounding and
performance capability is not good I
think it's because most of the model not
uh really to to chall their model for
the use and third one is most of the
model is uh to generate an action
directory without Reon so here is some
more concrete uh the the slides about
this three observation or
issues the first one you can see
uh they have different the the texture
representation um some like in the WB is
HTML maybe Dom tree and in the OS they
have another type of accessibility and
the mobile have different
one and most of and all them it's super
long super
lengthy and could be longer and longer
at the complexity of your
GUI
uh so com comparing with the the the
vision B pure Vision Bas vision is just
one so whatever your background code
looks like the the the the image is say
that is one um about the
the benefit of the gii AG the second one
is the uh the because of different
system use different tools the action
space is very different it it's not a
big issue but it's still a issue that it
will prevent this uh effective cross
development learning and also that you
cannot to leverage different data the
training data together
uh which uh not good for the this
scalability then it's this visual
grounding capability so here is we
tested on uh the the mobile desktop and
the WB
scenarios uh we found
the uh those close sourcing model from
surprising bad I see
so it means like the model doesn't
really to optimize for the computer use
scenario by this is tp4 gp4 the new one
operator all call 3.5 3.7 is and here is
a example like the current the existing
methods um they CH the agent to generate
the the low level actions directly like
this the P the director the code rather
than um the sophisticated the
reasoning
U reasoning concept
reasoning the the text uh which would do
make to to get the those those models or
those agents very struggle on on the
complex scenarios in the real world that
may require more careful planning
um which those planning could be
planning knowledge could be transferred
from the the tax uh tax cor which TR
inm so given those this uh uh these
three issues we uh propose this AR model
uh first is the pure Vision based so it
doesn't matter what it accessibility Tre
format is using in the in in a system or
in the web
browser and second is it this will
improve the the grounding model through
uh combine uh with Define a new unify
form format combine all the existing
data and the and the chel model uh to
improve grounding and third one is we
explicitly to include this reasoning
process
what we call it in the monologue into
our chaining the model chaining for the
uh for Action
generator uh as I said the for the AG uh
we eliminates these dependencies on the
platform specific textual representation
because this is a vision pure Vision
based it's directly operate on the
screen screen
images uh so it make the model could be
more more generalizable into different
interface uh and we we we we we
developed uh a standardized the the
action space that uh we could to uh
combine the different the data set into
the same the action format so that we
can leverage more
data the the the existing data
and the more crucial is the right side
is we in incorporate this in the
monologue during the
Channing uh which can um developly
sophisticated the reing
patterns uh and which through
through uh this uh by leveraging the the
knowledge or memories patterns is
already memorized inm
I think this is important uh uh to to to
build more more robust the this action
mod so in each interaction step uh the
our our
agent got to generate this uh in in the
monologue the two step two compon the uh
this two new two parts the S and the low
level
instructions uh between your
observation uh and the final
actions so through this way you could to
through this thought and the low level
instruction and action you can consider
this a this enables the the more the
agent can and do it step by step from
the different complexity because at the
beginning you get a high level
instruction and you doing this uh
thought like CH of thought so you uh
decompose the problem into some small
deps and with those stth you can you can
to generate this low level instruction
for each step about action and then you
can get a better the the the uh uh
concrete the code to access question so
then it make the make could make the
model be make the agent be more robust
uh more more accurate so that is the
motivation for for for the training we
have a two steps first step is the
grounding and the second step is the
planning and the reasoning and for
grounding uh we did some tricks uh which
is grounding packing strategy what do
you mean a grounding packing strategy is
like we were to uh find all the the
grounding PS the grounding samples which
based on the same image and we concat as
a
multi- grounding uh as one sample we
found that can improve the training
efficiency and even uh to have a bit
Improvement on the
performance and uh in the second stage
is uh we add this in the model loock in
our
training uh and the the which make the
the the agent could to generate this
intermediate thoughts uh and the low
level instructions before before they
generate action directly in the data
part uh as I said we because it's a pure
Vision based we can easily to combine
the Define the data set together uh and
Define a d format for the
outcome uh then we can leverage all the
all the most of the existing data and
create a new data set to CH our
model and for the
monologue we use we we prompt the
Frontier Model like a
tp40 uh given this the the the
observation image and highlight the UI
element with the F with the instr ction
and the final goal and the final the the
the code the action code and the from T4
tp4 to generate in the monologue
component so this is the example the
previous so the previous is on they have
the forms
instruction and previous action of
course the observation we we don't add
here and this action then later after
this step the
we they will we will have the the S and
the low level
instructions in the in the new data in
the new tring so this way we create the
AR collection which is combine a a
number of different data set um but then
we finally we get uh for stage one we
get the 1 million the gii grounding data
and for stage two we get the 35 MTI
so k m step trajectory which is explicit
in a monologue reasoning data it's great
and then we do same thing like we do
before we H we run our model we TR our
model on this agent AG collection data
set um and we demonstrate we showed this
this a model perform exceptional on the
the the grounding data grounding task so
the the top is the grounding task so
there's no planner we can see uh the a
significant output from the existing
models on on on on the on those
task and we also want the full the two
stage training so we also have the model
uh single model to both grounding and
planning reasoning
action and we found after you did the
plan the the second stage training it
even improve this grounding task uh and
and and achieve the state of art
performance and then we also did the
development this
evaluation uh on the offline setting uh
on mental lab it also showed it's
achieve the the superior performance
across different
metrics on the
offline and also on the Android setting
we also did the this evaluation on the
online setting which uh uh it's m web
and Andro World which is uh this m web
live is different M web M web uh it
provide a dynamic web based development
to to do the evaluation
um and then we can see the the the
performance uh of all the AR
model the the superior
performance and even better than so
uh and there one thing I want to uh
emphasize is if you see the here is AR
with 7B model with CPD 40
planner uh
it could be it perform the state of art
uh in this
tasks but which means like our uh the
our the aror model have a better
grounding capabilities and this
definitely can improve the uh the final
performance of uh the the this planner
task is at this uh planning
task and and this is not is also with
found like uh they still have a big
space to improve the grounding to
improve uh to which will improve the
final performance on the uh different
computer use and we do some analysis on
uh for different components in AR on
performance both stage one stage two is
important in the mo it's also very
crucial uh for both the the high level
reasoning and the low level ground dat
and we find in the monologue actually
helps solving the uh the harder task
which have which in the in the right
side you see one is self plan one enforc
plan enforced plan means we enforce it
to it must generate in the monologue and
it can uh achieve the 20% of resolve 20%
of the grounding
arrows and the right left side is the
two examples with and the result in the
model and we also find see the cross
platform benefits in the arist the arist
is TR on the web and mobile data o word
is a computer use uh we F it's
remarkably although we uh we didn't uh
uh CH
exclusively on the this computer use
scenario uh the model still perform
pretty good uh and uh and with and with
using AG 72b as a grounding plus4 is
even the it's just even better than how
a computer
use so so here uh I want take a here I
want to to uh you can take away is first
uh the
model uh is a unified
framework
uh it can Pro it can it perform Prett
robust across different platform with
only uh visual
observation and I think the the video
this pure Vision Paradigm uh is have a
big advantages on the computer use or
GUI uh use case which I think open I
already agree with uh this uh this this
uh my comment because they have
operator and the second is although we
have a lot of progress uh we still need
to improve both grounding and the
structural reasoning uh don't just try
to improve reasoning actually they have
bigger bigger space uh layer you need to
improve in the grounding side